听好了  观众们
That's right, folks.
请勿在家尝试本片中的任何实验
Don't try this at home.
我们就是你们所称的专家
We're what you call experts.
本集《流言终结者》为您呈现
On this episode of "Mythbusters"...
显然  一个乒乓球足以致命
Apparently a ping-pong ball can kill you.
击出  瞄准  还有舞蹈
Yep. Duck, cover, and, uh, dance?
为测试两条有关致命炮弹的流言
To tackle a duo of deadly ballistic mysteries...
搞个毛啊
What the ........
这太离谱了
Nothing's making any sense.
节目组进行了一场独具匠心的
The team engages in an arms race...
一点皮肉伤而已
It's just a flesh wound.
"军备竞赛"
of incredible ingenuity.
首先  在一次史无前例的尝试中
First, in a world-record-breaking attempt...
从没有人这么做过
This has never been done before.
有点吓人啊
It's scary.
杰米和亚当提出疑问
Jamie and Adam ask,
-"乒乓球能否使人丧命"  -发射
- "Will ping-pong make a mortal mark?"   - Go!
那是我最爱的爆炸声
That was an ever-loving smack of a bang.
接着  卡莉  格兰特和托里即将感受
Then, Kari, Grant, and Tory feel the force...
我是你的父亲
I am your father.
沙皇时代的战争威力
in a tsar war.
冰制的大炮
Will an ice cannon...
一
One.
真能赶走疯狂的入侵者吗
really blow the daft invaders away?
更多精彩好戏  尽在本期《流言终结者》
A lot of drama here on the set of "Mythbusters."
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
流言终结者是何方神圣
Who are the Mythbusters?
亚当·沙维奇
Adam Savage...
我拒绝你的真实性并将用我的来代替
I reject your reality and substitute my own.
杰米·海曼
And Jamie Hyneman.
永别了
Bye-bye!
他们有超过三十年的特技经验
Between them, more than 30 years of special-effects experience.
翻译：cindysheva  foolyangyang
和他们二位一道的是格兰特·今原
Together with Grant Imahara...
翻译：姚小事儿  兮之  Wei2321L
太刺激了
That is crazy!
卡莉·拜伦
Kari Byron...
翻译：横排混血  Foxer
超级省油
Hyper-mile that!
还有托里·贝鲁奇
and Tory Belleci.
这回是玩真的了
It's about to get real.
轴轴：雪贵人  小狱
他们不光叙述流言
They don't just tell the myths.
他们还将流言付诸实践
They put them to the test.
校对：吃货丁小七  萌Su
流言终结者
第十三季 第八集
后期：8T
首先  亚当和杰米将验证一条有关
First up, Adam and Jamie tackle the tall tale
乒乓球可以致命的荒诞流言
that ping-pong can go lethally wrong.
乒乓球杀手
没搞错吧
Really?
乒乓球可以致命吗
A ping-pong ball can kill you?
流言就是这么说的
That's the myth.
它的质量太小
There's no way it has enough mass
不足以贯穿任何物体
to actually penetrate anything.
18比0
18 to nothing.
但要是球的速度非常  非常快呢
But what if the ball was going really, really fast?
已经够了
Enough already!
这是一个有趣的物理谜题
It's an interesting physical conundrum.
如此轻巧脆弱的小物件
Can such a delicate object with so little mass
能否达到子弹的杀伤力呢
achieve ballistic lethality?
能否让乒乓球达到足以致命的
Is it possible to fire plastic ping-pong balls fast enough
发射速度呢
to result in mortal damage?
如果你打算用小小的乒乓球杀人
So, if you're thinking an itty-bitty ping-pong ball
你会怎么做
can kill you, what's your plan?
力的大小
Well, force...
等于质量
equals mass...
乘以加速度
times acceleration.
我明白了
Ah, I see.
既然这个欠缺质量
So, what this lacks in mass,
你希望通过速度来弥补
you're hoping to make up for in speed.
你觉得它要多快才行
How fast are you thinking of going?
非常快  我在考虑超音速
A lot. I'm thinking supersonic.
太棒了  我们该从哪开始
I love it. Where should we start?
人力加速吗
Human power?
去打几个回合
Go down, bat a few of these around,
看看我们挥拍能让它飞多快吗
and see how fast we can make them go?
-没错  -好主意
- Yep. - Sounds great.
在他们通过机械加速让球速
And before the guys attempt to mechanically
达到超音速之前
ramp it up to supersonic,
■
乒乓球发球机
需要测试下杰米认为可能致命的最低速度
The minimum that Jamie thinks is required for a lethal hit.
我们的非专业运动员们
Our less-than-professional players
对人力加速实验全力以赴
have given the manual speed test everything they've got.
杰米的雷霆一击让球的离拍速度
So, Jamie was able to rocket the ball off of his paddle
达到每小时109.4公里
at 68 miles an hour.
109.4公里/小时
我则让球加速到了每小时117.5公里
I was able to do it at 75 miles per hour.
117.5公里/小时
这两个速度  都离致命差得远呢
Neither of those speeds, anywhere close to lethal.
但我有了一个能让它飞得更快些的主意
But I have an idea for getting it to go a bit faster.
就你了
Ah! Perfect.
我准备付诸实践
I'm gonna build it.
他们的徒手之力显然
Their hands-on technique obviously failed
无法达到致命效果
to fuel a fatal force.
所以亚当组装了
So, Adam puts together
一把气压动力的乒乓气枪
an air-pressure-powered ping-pong popgun.
它的原理是这样
Here's how this works.
我把这叫做后装式气枪
This is what I call a breech-loading popgun.
这是后膛  这是子弹
Here's the breech. There's the ammo.
装入子弹  从这里加压
Seal it up. Pressurize from here.
打开开关
Open it up.
对准你想要乒乓球子弹射击的方向
Point it in the direction ou want to hit with a ping-pong ball.
打开这个高气压阀门
Release with this high-pressure valve.
然后你就瞧好吧
And Bob's your uncle.
瞧好是什么意思呢
What does Bob's your uncle mean?
意思就是但愿我们能让乒乓球加速到
Well, it means hopefully that we've gotten the ping-pong ball
不可思议的高速
to an impossibly large speed.
增压泵加压到气枪所能承受的
And with the pressure pump to the max
最大压力  大约是...
the popgun can handle, a modest...
655千帕发射实验  倒数三
95 P.S.I. In 3.
我们拭目以待
We're about to find out.
速度达到每小时225.3公里
140 miles per hour.
对于这样的小型设备来说算是不错的数据
Nice for a little device like that.
发射
Here we go.
还是不致命
It's not lethal, though.
我们离做到这点还差得远呢
We've got a long ways to go before we get to that point.
正如布罗迪所说
Yep. As Brody would say,
Jason Brody  杰森·布罗迪  射击游戏《孤岛惊魂》主角
他们要做一根更长的枪管
they're gonna need a bigger barrel.
人力挥拍的球速是每小时112.6公里
Our paddles got the ping-pong balls to about 70 miles an hour.
而我们这把小气枪
My little shooter here,
达到了每小时225.3公里  等等
up to 140 --Wait a second.
剪辑师  能给我这动作加个枪声特效吗
Editors, can you give me a nice shotgun sound effect for this?
感觉帅多了
Much better.
69万帕压强  时速225.3公里
Got the ping-pong ball up to 140 miles an hour at 100 P.S.I.
根据杰米和我的经验
Jamie's and my experience,
压强并不是空气炮中
P.S.I. is not the deciding factor
子弹加速的决定性因素
for acceleration in an air cannon.
炮筒长度才是
It's barrel length.
所以我想我们要再做一支
So, I think what we need to do is build another one of these
枪筒很长  很长的气枪
with a really, really long barrel.
接下来为您带来
Up next...
一条流年代久远冷的冰冰的炮弹流言
An age-old, ice-cold ballistics mystery from history.
冰加农炮
希望你们带上保暖设备
Well, I hope you guys packed your thermals,
因为这条流言来自
Because this myth comes from
深冬时节的中世纪俄国
the depths of winter in medieval Russia.
有个小镇被包围了
Now, there was a town. It was under siege.
他们没有任何用来自我防卫的东西
And they didn't have anything to defend themselves with.
所以他们临时做出了大炮和炮弹
So, they improvised a cannon and cannonballs
用的就是他们唯一充足的资源
out of the one thing they had plenty of.
冰
Ice.
真的吗  只有冰
Really? Just ice?
是的  冰  也许还混有一些加固材料
Yes! Ice, possibly some materials to strengthen it.
但历史书上写到
But the history books say
这是行之有效的抵御武器
it was a viable defensive weapon.
好消息就是如果冰河时代再次降临
Well, the good news is if there's another ice age
《僵尸启示录》的故事成了真
and the Zombie Apocalypse happens,
我们就有用来打击它们的武器了
we'll have something to fight them off with.
的确  有备无患总是好的
Well, it's really good to be prepared for...
不管什么事
everything.
我一向如此
I'm always prepared.
按照推测  在濒临绝境的最后时刻
Supposedly, in the ultimate test of backs-to-the-wall,
哥萨克人灵光一现
improvised ingenuity, the Cossacks crafted a cannon
用最不可能的原料制出了一门大炮
out of the most unlikely material imaginable --
冰冻的水
frozen water.
你还记得很久很久以前
All right, now, you remember a million years ago,
我们刚刚开始这个节目的时候
when we first started on this show,
曾经实验过冰子弹
we tested ice bullets.
就在我们射击步枪的时候
And as soon as we shot the rifle,
子弹就变成气体了
the bullet turned to gases.
正因如此我认为
Which is exactly why I think
在我们制造原尺寸的冰炮之前
that before we go and build a full-size ice cannon,
我们应该先实验炮弹
we should start by testing the cannonballs.
没错  如果炮弹不能保持形状
Right, because if the cannonballs can't hold together,
流言就已经被终结了
then the myth is already busted.
没错  所以我们开始吧
Exactly. So, why don't we do this?
做一些冰炮弹
Let's make some ice cannonballs.
我们先用真正的炮弹射击
We'll fire them out of a real cannon
然后再继续
and take it from there.
好的  我喜欢
Good. I like it.
他们曾经的失败
The team's previous failure
冰块子弹S01E01
射击冰冻的水子弹
firing frozen H2O ammo...
根本做不到
It just can't be done.
最后只有汽化了的水
You're gonna end up with vaporized water.
意味着西伯利亚围困故事中
means the opening salvo in this Siberian siege story
万弹齐发的最薄弱点在于
will be the weakest link --
投射物本身
the projectiles themselves.
我们做了很多调查
We've done a lot of research
尝试找到任何有关
to see if we could find any sort of historical information...
冰炮弹规格的历史资料
on the specs of the ice cannonballs.
我们发现他们可能用纤维进行了加固
Now, we've found that they may have been reinforced with fibers
比如大麻  木头和浆纸
such as hemp, wood, and paper pulp.
托里和我负责有填充物的炮弹
So while Tory and I work on the supplemented cannonballs,
而格兰特将制造纯净的冰炮弹
Grant's gonna work on the clear ice ones.
你在后面干什么呢
What is going on back there?
用天然材料
So, using natural materials
作为加固结构的替代品
for structurally stronger alternatives...
锯末
Sawdust.
他们做了四种冰炮弹
the team makes four types of frozen cannonballs.
这个炮弹应该够劲
Yeah! This is gonna be one strong cannonball.
-纯净的冰  -太棒了
- Pure ice...  - Perfect.
加了大麻的冰
and ice plus hemp...
冰炮弹里加入大麻
Ice ball with hemp in it.
锯末和纸
sawdust and paper.
这个太棒了
Whoa, that is awesome.
-很漂亮  -看看多漂亮
- That's beautiful. - Look at how perfect that is.
投射物到位了
With their projectiles prepped,
该去适当的爆炸地点了
it's off to a suitably explosive location.
好了
All right.
-把大炮拿出来吧  -好的
- Let's bring out the cannon. - All right.
哈利·韦伯带来了奥摩西大炮
Harry Webb has brought out Old Moses
以便我们实验各种成分的冰炮弹
so that we can test each recipe for our ice cannonballs
看看哪一种能承受住真正大炮的爆炸
and see which one can withstand the blast of a real cannon.
我们将逐渐加大火药量
We're gonna be firing our cannonballs
来发射冰炮弹
with increasingly larger amounts of black powder
看它们能否经得住压力
to see if they can withstand the pressure.
我们从纯净的冰炮弹开始
We're starting with pure ice cannonballs
用大概230克黑火药
and 8 ounces of black powder,
这是大炮可以用的最小值
the minimum amount we can use in the cannon.
别担心  哥们
Don't worry, comrade.
只是冰而已
They are only shooting ice.
能有多疼
How bad could that hurt?
正好拿来冰镇伏特加
We'll use it to chill our vodka.
我们立起网格以收集速度数据
We've set up our grid to collect some data on speed
并设立一个目标
and also added a target.
来吧  一起在战场上舞起来
Hey, come on, let's go dance at the battle.
实验一的准备都做好了
So, it's all go for test one.
装弹
We are loaded.
装弹了
Loaded!
一个纯净的冰炮弹和半斤的黑火药
A pure ice cannonball and half a pound of black powder
炮口动能也许能达到两万焦耳
with a potential muzzle energy of 20,000 joules.
闭眼捂耳朵
Eyes and ears!
无疑  这个雪球根本不可能保持形状
Surely, it doesn't stand a snowball's chance in hell of surviving.
准备开火  三
Firing! Three...
更不要提对跳舞的假人有什么伤害
Let alone doing any damage to our dancing dummy.
一
One.
太棒了
Wow! That was awesome.
看起来射击很成功
That looked like a very successful hit.
看起来我们击中了个坏人
It looks like we hit the bad guy.
而且把他打倒了
And knocked him down.
我被吓到了
I am totally shocked.
纯净的冰炮弹不只
Not only did the pure ice cannonball
毫发无伤的被射击出来
come out completely intact,
并达到了每秒300米
but it was traveling 1,000 feet per second,
每格0.3米  0.3米/毫秒=300米/秒
300米/秒*3600秒/小时=1080公里/小时
即每小时1080公里的速度
or 680 miles an hour.
这意味着如果我们把大炮稍微瞄高一点
That means if we aim our cannon just a little bit up,
就能达到非常远的一段距离
we could have traveled an incredible distance.
这个结果真不可思议
It is an incredible result.
奥摩西大炮的威力没能分解冰冻的水
The might power of Old Moses couldn't part the frozen water.
它毫发无伤的以每小时1080公里的
It stayed intact and hit the target
致命速度击中了目标
at a lethal 680 miles per hour.
不好意思  朋友
Sorry, my friend.
我们低估了冰的威力
I guess we underestimated the ice.
这样惊人的结果意味着流言可以
And such an impressive result means the myth can proceed
不加任何辅助材料以最纯净的形式继续了
in its purest form, without supplementary materials.
问题是  纯净的冰能达到多快的速度
The question is, how fast can pure H2O go?
我们要加料
We're gonna go up
加到680克黑火药
to a pound and a half of black powder...
这是这门大炮能承受的最大值
which is the most that this cannon can handle.
我们拭目以待
Let's see what happens.
三  二  一
Three, two, one!
这真是
That was...
奥摩西大炮发出了它能承受的最强的爆炸
Old Moses supplies the biggest boom he can handle.
最高速度达到了
And with a top speed topping out
680克黑火药=每小时2500公里
难以置信的每小时2500公里
at an astonishing 1,550 miles per hour,
冰炮弹超过了所有的预期
the ice has exceeded all expectations.
接下来
Coming up...
越大
Is bigger...
真的越好吗
really better?
真大
That's big.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
拿球拍的杰米说
Jamie the paddle says...
我们很有效率地试尝试了
we've effectively been attempting to weaponize
将3克的乒乓球变成武器
the one-tenth of an ounce ping-pong ball
并使其致命
and make it lethal.
起初我们用球拍对球一顿猛抽
So we started out smacking them with rackets as hard as we can,
最高只能达到每小时120公里的速度
and came up with about 75 miles per hour off the racket.
因此我们造了这么一个宝贝
So, I built this little baby right here.
辅以约五十万帕的高压
And at 90 psi,
我们能将乒乓球加速到
we were able to shoot Ping-Pong balls from this
每小时225公里
at 140 miles per hour.
225公里/小时
仍然不够致命
Still not really lethal.
不过依此类推
But continuing along this theme,
我们相信只要我们的装备再大一点
we figure if we make something that's a little bigger,
我的玩具枪
My little popgun.
比方说大20倍  也许能管用
say, 20 times as big. We might get some real results.
为了打造致命一击
So, in attempt to do some deadly damage,
亚当和杰米将装置的长度延长到极致
Adam and Jamie are going to extreme lengths.
效果拔群
It's coming along nicely.
长达24米
80 feet, to be exact.
其中的奥秘
And exactly why?
让海曼为您娓娓道来...
Well, a Hyneman walks into a bar and says...
为什么要这么长的枪管
So, why the long barrel?
只要乒乓球后方的气压
Well, as long as the pressure behind the ball
大于前方的气压
is greater than the pressure in front of the ball,
乒乓球就会持续加速
the ball's gonna continue to accelerate.
完美
It's perfect.
因此  枪管越长
And so, the longer the barrel we have,
加速的时间越长
the more time the ball will have to do that,
乒乓球射出的初速度就越高
and the faster it'll be going when it comes out the far end.
这是目标
Here's the target.
等气枪被压力罐完全加压之后...
And with the popgun pressurized to the max the shop air can supply...
好的  现在差不多一百万帕了
Okay, that's 140 psi.
装弹...
it's time to load...
这些都是专业级别的乒乓球
These are some professional-grade Ping-Pong balls.
锁定...
and lock...
闩上后膛
Close the breech!
-蓄力一击  -危险区域
- and let rip. - Range is hot!
开火
Firing.
三  二  一
Three, two, one.
我只看到那头有个洞
I just see a hole at the other end.
这次猛多了
That is far out.
真是颗快得没影的乒乓球
That's a fast little Ping-Pong ball.
依靠24米的枪管  这只乒乓球的速度
Well, our 80-foot-long barrel sent this Ping-Pong ball
足以贯穿2.5厘米厚的蜂巢紙板
through an inch-thick piece of honeycomb cardboard,
真是太快了
虽然本身这也没什么大不了
which in and of itself is not that incredible a feat.
但它居然能在2厘米厚的胶合板上留下印记
But it left a visible mark on 3/4-inch plywood.
确实出乎我的意料
That is something more than I expected.
秒杀纸板显然是没什么问题
It certainly banged up the backboard.
真是太快了
不过最终的速度究竟是多少呢
But what about the crunched numbers?
每小时730公里
453 miles per hour.
挺有希望的
That's a good place to start.
绝对的
Absolutely.
730公里/小时
我们将乒乓球加速到每小时730公里
So, we got this ball going 453 miles per hour.
真是太快了
的确是很快
That's really fast,
不过我还是要说  这不够致命
But I have to say, I don't think it's lethal.
根据我在实验中的观察
Based on what I'm seeing with this ball,
这种速度可以击断肋骨
it might break a rib,
并且造成瘀伤
it might give you a really nasty bruise,
但仍然不够致命
but it's not gonna kill you.
因此  为了那致命一击
So, to make a mortal mark,
他们还需要更高的速度  更大的动量
they're going to need more speed, more momentum,
120公里/小时
225公里/小时
730公里/小时
继续探索
and a step into the unknown.
这是前所未有的
This has never been done before.
有点怕怕
It's scary.
卡莉  格兰特和托里正在验证
Kari, Grant, and Tory are testing the ultimate
背水一战中的终极弹道工程奇迹
in backs-to-the-wall ballistics ingenuity.
直到现在...
And so far...
别担心  哥们
don't worry, comrade.
都只是前戏阶段
it's all go on the fro-blow.
对不住了  兄弟
Sorry, my friend.
我们低估了冰的威力
I guess we underestimated the ice.
炮弹已经就绪  现在轮到炮筒了
The team has the balls. Now to build the barrel.
这是一个巨型硬卡纸筒
Now, what I have here is a giant cardboard tube.
大伙都没事吧
Everybody okay?
我们打算这样建造冰雪大炮
Now, this is how we're gonna make our ice cannons.
我们将在这个炮筒模具中注满水
This is the mold that we're gonna fill up with water
然后冷冻结冰  大功告成
and let it freeze so we can make our cannon.
我要做几个尺寸不同的版本
So, I'm gonna build a couple of different sizes,
并且测试哪一种最为坚固
and we're gonna see which one is the strongest
能够承受黑火药爆炸的威力
to withstand the exploding black powder.
主管
没错  谈到大炮
Yep, when it comes to cannons,
辅管
后膛
追管
辅管炮头
尺寸的确很重要
size really does matter.
后膛
后膛  即炮管末端黑火药爆炸的场所
The breech, that is the explosive chamber at the base of the barrel,
后膛
必须要能承受爆炸产生的巨大压力
has to contain and channel
并且将其能量引向炮弹
the energy of the black-powder blast.
为了找到最优的形态结构
So to find the optimal dimension,
托里制作了三种规格的后膛
Tory is building 3 breeches
三种后膛规格
管壁分别为10  15和20厘米
with 4-, 6-, and 8-inch walls
10厘米
15厘米
20厘米
管外径分别为30  38 和51厘米
and diameters of 12, 16, and 20 inches.
管壁太薄  炮身容易炸毁
Too thin, and it'll explode.
管壁太厚  炮身将无法移动
Too thick, and the mass becomes structurally prohibitive to move around.
好了  纸筒中已经灌满了水
All right, so now that the tubes are filled up with water.
只需静待筒里的水结冰
We just need to let them freeze,
后膛就制成了
and then we'll have our breeches.
一周后  冰冷的大炮
And one week later, the ice-cold cannons
第  一  二  三  四  五  六 七  天
被冷冻货车送至爆破实验场
are ready for a refrigerated trip to the bomb range.
肯定很有趣
This is gonna be fun.
我们已经知道230克黑火药
So, we now know that half a pound of black powder is enough
足以将冰雪炮弹加速至时速1080公里
to propel our ice cannonball at 680 miles per hour,
每格0.3米  0.3米/毫秒=300米/秒
300米/秒*3600秒/小时=1080公里/小时
这样的射击范围和杀伤威力足以致命
which should give us enough range and enough damage to be a viable weapon.
现在该轮到冰制后膛登场了
Now what we need to do is work on the breech.
这玩意要是倒下来就惨了
God, it would suck if this thing fell.
我们有10  15和20厘米三种规格
We have a 4-inch wall, a 6-inch wall, and an 8-inch wall.
我们将在他们中分别置入230克黑火药
We'll put our half-pound of black powder in there
看看他们当中究竟哪个能够
And see which one of these, if any, is able to survive
在爆炸一瞬的巨大压力下幸存下来
the kinds of forces that are generated in a cannon.
首先亮相的是51厘米管外径
First up is the 20-inch breech
厚度20厘米的后膛...
with 8-inch walls...
别松手
Don't let go.
老天
Oh, my god!
也许除了测试230克黑火药的爆炸之外
where surviving the half-pound black-powder blast
终结者手头还有别的棘手问题
may not be the only issue.
我得说
I got to tell you,
跟冰块打交道可不是件容易的活
I can see some problems with working with ice.
没错  我也搞不懂
Yeah, I don't know how these guys
当年这些家伙是怎么驾驭这种武器的
would've been able to actually maneuver an ice cannon.
冰块的质量是个大问题
Mass is a big concern.
质量越大
The larger it is,
越难建造  搬运  操纵
the harder it'll be to build, move, and manipulate.
此外  即使是在天寒地冻的三九...
Plus, even in the deepest mid-winter...
置入引线
Loading the charge now.
由于冰的隔热性
due to the insulating properties of ice,
冷冻大量的水需要很长时间...
freezing large amounts of water takes a long time...
好了  准备就绪  我们去观测室吧
All right, we're set. Let's go to the bunker.
这意味着
meaning the smallest breech
能盛装炸药的最小后膛将是最佳选择
that can contain the blast will be the best option.
那么  在没有炮弹仅有火药的情况下
So, with the black powder loaded and no projectile,
哪个炮管能经受住呢
which barrel will survive?
好的  直径51厘米后膛测试实验
All right! This is 20-inch diameter breech.
倒数三  二  一
In three, two, one.
我们刚刚想出了快速制造冰雹的方法
Well, we just figured out a way to make hail instantly.
巨型雪锥
Giant snow cone.
现在  情况并未按预期发展
Now, that did not go according to plan.
这样就行不通了
That's not gonna work.
那已经是我们做的最厚的后膛了
That is the thickest wall we have.
现在的情况对这条流言很不利
Right now, it is not looking good for the myth.
但也可能是我们的火药放多了
But you know what? Maybe we're using too much black powder.
可能我们需要找到火药的最佳量
Maybe we need to find the perfect amount of black powder
才能够既发射出炮弹又不会破坏大炮
to launch the cannonball and not destroy our cannon.
因此  由于51厘米的后膛数量有限
So, with a few more freshly frozen 20-inch breeches,
所以团队决定降低爆炸强度
the team decides a little less boom is required
而不是增加后膛厚度
and not more ice.
他们将火药量
They're scaling down the black powder
由225克减至只有35克
from 8 to a mere 1.25 ounces.
如果51厘米的后膛仍然无法承受...
If the 20-inch breech can't handle this...
好了  我们的大炮准备就绪
All right, our cannon is hot.
那么这条流言肯定被终结了
the myth is surely busted.
倒数三  二  一
In three, two, one.
-我想它做到了  -成功了
- I think it did it. - It worked!
这次后膛没有和火药一起爆炸
We shot the plug out without blowing up the breech!
这算不上什么大爆炸  但却开了个好头
It was a somewhat less-than-big boom, but it's a start.
我们的后膛没有爆炸
Our breech hasn't exploded.
仍然完好无损  意味着它可以重复使用
It's still intact, which means it's reusable.
我们继续  这回放入50克
We're gonna keep going. 1.75 is next.
好了  冰制后膛填弹完毕锁定目标
All right, ice breech locked and loaded.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
倒数三  二  一
In three, two, one.
这次更剧烈些
Now, that was more aggressive.
但一个全新的后膛能承受57克火药吗
But can a brand-new breech contain 2 ounces?
57克火药  倒数三  二  一
2 ounces, in three, two, one.
好吧  看来这就有点太多了
Oh. All right, it looks like that was too much.
那么50克就是最佳剂量了
I guess one and three-quarter ounces, that's the perfect amount.
没错  57克有点多了
Yeah, two is just a bit too much.
我们准备好了炮弹
So, we've got the ball.
纯冰制加农炮
合适剂量的火药
We've got the amount of black powder.
50克火药
以及合适尺寸的后膛
We've got the size of the breech.
20厘米厚
直径50厘米
知道这意味着什么吗
You know what that means.
这意味着现在该建一个全尺寸的大炮
That means it's time to build a full-size cannon
并大胆一试了
and go for it.
稍后...
Later...
好了  等等
Okay, wait, ooh.
怨声载道...
the game of moans...
搞毛啊
What the xx?
全都没有意义
Nothing's making any sense.
继续上演
continues.
一
One.
亚当和杰米有一支超大尺寸乒乓球玩具枪
Adam and jamie have a super-sized ping-pong popgun,
而且他们用起来毫无顾忌
and they're not afraid to use it.
虽然以每小时720公里的速度
But while shooting aesthetically pleasing objects
射击各种物体的效果令人印象深刻
at 450 miles an hour is impressive,
但他们认为其产生的破坏力并不致命
they determined the resulting destruction is less than lethal.
那么 接下来是什么呢
So, what next?
它可能会导致肋骨骨折  但肯定不致命
It might break a rib, but it's not gonna kill you.
120公里/小时
亚当偶然发现了
Well, Adam has chanced upon
225公里/小时
730公里/小时
一种叫做互联网的"前沿科技资源"
a cutting-edge resource called the, er, Internet.
太神奇了
That's amazing.
看来物理老师们
It turns out that physics teachers
不需要24米长的管子
have been getting incredible acceleration
就能让乒乓球获得超大加速度了
out of ping-pong balls without using 80-foot-long barrels.
我觉得我们应该立刻来检验一下
And I think it's a method that we should investigate immediately.
好了  不错  运转正常
Okay, cool, it's working all right.
他们的方法是
What they've been doing is,
准备一根90厘米长的聚氯乙烯管
they've been taking a 36-inch-long tube of PVC,
把乒乓球放在一端
and they've been putting a ping-pong ball in one end.
然后在管子两端贴上胶带
Then, they put packing tape over each end of the tube
用真空吸尘器吸空管子里的空气
and they use a vacuum to draw a full vacuum in that tube.
明白
Okay.
好了  打开真空吸尘器
Here we go. Pulling the vacuum.
然后  当他们捅破一端的胶带后
Then, when they pierce that side, of course,
空气就会进入  填补真空空间
air wants to rush in to fill the vacuum,
但乒乓球挡在了中间
but the ping-pong ball's in the way.
因此  它会被往前推动
So, it starts to move forward.
大家都往后退点儿
Just, everyone back off a little bit.
因为是真空的  所以乒乓球前方
There's nothing in its way in terms of air
没有任何气体阻碍
because there's a vacuum.
所以  它从这端喷出时的速度
And so, it bursts out of this side
超过了每小时480公里
at something over 300 miles per hour.
这只是理论
That's the theory.
开始了
Here we go!
太牛逼了
Holy xx!
天哪  真是不错啊
Oh, man, that was really good.
没想到这方法这么管用
I didn't expect it to work that well.
90厘米管子的实验效果惊人
The 3-foot prototype worked scarily well.
戳破密封的真空空间后  空气突然涌入
Popping the sealed vacuum caused a sudden influx of air,
由此产生的压力的变化使乒乓球飞速向前
and the pressure differential sends the ball rocketing.
在几次技术性调整...
And after a few technique tweaks...
一
One.
以及把管子增长一倍后...
and a double-barrel length...
一
One!
亚当测量到的球速是
Adam measures rocketing at
每小时600公里
375 miles an hour.
真是相当惊人
That is mighty respectable.
惊人到成为新的乒乓球
Respectable enough to be the new
弹射动力最佳选择
ping-pong projectile power of choice.
600公里/小时
利用真空吸尘器
Well, the vacuum trick for launching a ping-pong ball
将乒乓球射出短管的方法非常成功
out of a short length of tubing is working gangbusters.
乒乓球射出这个仅180厘米长的管子时
I actually got 375 miles an hour on a ping-pong ball
速度达到了每小时600公里
out of this measly 6-foot tube.
这太厉害了
That is awesome,
接下来我要集中精力
and this is where I'm gonna concentrate my energy
让乒乓球移动得最快
to get the fastest ping-pong ball possible.
好了  准备好了
All right, we're ready.
根据管子越大越好的理论...
Based on the theory that bigger barrels are better...
-把它抽空要多花些时间了  -是啊
- Heh, it's taking a little longer to pump this out. - Yeah.
他们把真空泵装在了巨大的24米长管上
the guys have rigged the vacuum pump to their enormous 80-footer.
他们忧心忡忡
There's plenty of nerves.
以前从没这么做过
This has never been done before.
有点怕怕
It's scary.
他们翘首期盼...
High expectations...
世界首例即将呈现
Here's a world first.
真空管中聚集的能力也蓄势待发
and energy waiting to fulfill its potential.
乒乓球火箭筒发射倒数三  二  一
Ping-pong bazooka in three, two, one!
但是这是一发出乎意料又让人失望的哑弹
But it's an unexpected and disappointing dud.
这次不行
Ah. That's no good.
这是我们的乒乓球
Here's our ping-pong ball.
那边是我们希望乒乓球
That wall is where we want the ping-pong ball
击中的墙壁
to be embedded in.
一
One!
此事必有蹊跷
Something's not working.
它已经很靠近管道的出口了
But it's reaching close to the end of our tube,
然后却莫名其妙地开始向后弹
and then somehow bouncing back a little.
其实并非莫名其妙
Well, not somehow.
瞧  空气从乒乓球后部涌入管中
See, air rushes in this tube behind the ping-pong ball.
而它的前面就是真空
There's a vacuum in front of it.
但是空气从间隙越过了乒乓球
But that air sneaks past the ping-pong ball,
然后起到了一个缓冲的作用
and it looks like it's providing a cushion
这使得乒乓球一到出口处就
that's actually causing it to spring back
弹了回来
once it reaches the end.
它的速度或动量不足以它冲出去
So, it's not attaining enough speed or momentum to bust out.
-一  -不行
- One. - Nope.
还是不行
Didn't make it.
这说明我们把管道做得太长了
That tells me that we've made this tube too long.
是的  这个气垫令乒乓球减速
Yep, that cushion of air decelerates the ball
到力量不足以冲破
to the point that it doesn't have the force
封口的胶带
to pop the packing tape.
与期待相反
So, as Brody wouldn't say,
他们需要短一点的管道
they need a shorter barrel.
问题是多短合适呢
The question is how short?
我们将利用高速摄像机来找出
We're gonna use the high-speed camera to find out
乒乓球在哪里速度最高
where the ping-pong ball is no longer accelerating.
然后我就在那里把管道切断
Then I'm gonna cut the barrel there
希望这么做能起作用
and hope that that works.
好的  速度测试  准备开始
All right, speed test, here we go.
三  二  一
Three, two, one!
280米/秒
2.4米
数次测试
Several tests...
324米/秒
4.9米
和计算之后
and sums later...
一
One.
他们发现乒乓球在管道九米处
they find the ball maxes out 30 feet along the barrel
达到了令人震惊的速度
at an astonishing velocity.
每秒370米
829.
速度超过了一马赫[一倍声速]
We're well past mach 1 here.
370米/秒
9米
在所需长度下重新实验
So, a quick reset at the requisite length...
真是不容易啊
Hoo. Boy, was that tough.
他们希望...
And the guys are expecting...
开始吧
Let's do it.
乒乓球能够以超过360米/秒的速度
the ball to bust out of the packing tape
-冲破胶带  -三  二  一
- at over 800 miles per hour. - Three, two, one!
那可是一个超音速的乒乓球
That would be a supersonic ping-pong ball.
听起来好快
Sounded fast.
但谁知道这意味着什么
But who knows what that meant?
这意味着
What it means is...
只有每秒122米
275 miles per hour.
九米长管道的出速度
We're getting less out of a 30-foot barrel
比1.8米长的还要低
than I was out of a 6-foot barrel.
一个令人沮丧的计算错误
a frustrating miscalculation.
怎么回事
What the fuck?
出口的速度只有每秒86米
It's only coming out of the barrel at 192 miles an hour.
更短的管道令
The shorter barrel means
乒乓球加速到了足以冲破胶带
the ball is now accelerating enough that it can burst free.
但是气垫的问题仍未解决
But the air cushion is still an issue.
尽管我们看到管道内最高速度
Even though we're seeing speeds upward of
可以超过每秒360米
800 miles per hour inside the tube,
370米/秒
9米
但是当乒乓球离开管道时
by the time the ball leaves the end of the tube,
86米/秒
速度却下降到了不足每秒90米
it's been decelerated to well under 200 miles an hour.
这个速度完全不致命
And that's not lethal.
目前来看  实验不怎么顺利
Yep. So far, this myth is misfiring.
前路非常不乐观
Failure is apparently the only option.
回到爆炸总部
Back at big boom HQ...
大家小心了  我们有冰制大炮
Look out, people! We have an ice cannon!
到了干正事的时候了
it's time to get down to business.
大炮放在这里
Cannon goes here.
我们回到天使村
We've come back to angels camp
来最终测试我们冰制大炮的流言
to do the final experiment in our ice cannon myth.
30米
100 feet.
目前来看还是很让人惊奇的
Now, so far, it's been very surprising.
我们已经知道了冰制炮弹可以
We learned that ice cannonballs actually stay intact
有效发射
and can go the distance.
这里  137米  在这里设置目标吧
Right here, 150 yards. Let's set up our target.
现在我们要实验冰制大炮...
Now we're gonna find out if an ice cannon...
该布置敌军了
Time to deploy the army.
能否发射冰制炮弹了
can shoot an ice cannonball.
战斗开始了
It's time to go to war.
流言是否属实的标准也就确定了
So, this sets up the criteria for our myth.
首先  冰制大炮得有足够的射程
Number one, the ice cannon has to have sufficient range,
第一  距离=137米
也就是差不多137米
meaning that it has to fire about 150 yards.
第二  足够的威力
其次  它的威力要足够大
Number two, it has to cause significant damage.
这是一个家庭节目
This is a family show.
但这个可不是一般商店里买的东西
This isn't quite from a family store.
所以我们得稍微修饰一下
We might have to do a little bit of censoring.
第三  可多次使用
再次  大炮要可重复使用
And number three, it has to be reusable.
一次性的可不行
One-time-only doesn't work.
好多了
That's better.
第一  距离=137米
第二  足够的威力
第三  可多次使用
若冰制大炮达到了这三条标准
If the ice cannon meets all three of these criteria,
那我们就可以认为流言是可能的
then we can call this myth plausible.
他们在运什么出来呢
What is that they're wheeling out?
他们运出来一个实际尺寸的大炮
What they're wheeling out is a full-size cannon.
它有根1.5米长
with a 5-foot-long,
直径0.5米的炮管
20-inch diameter barrel.
真是冰冻工程学的神奇壮举
It's a fantastic feat of frozen engineering.
质量虽然夸张
The extreme mass
但是结构却不够坚固...
coupled with the lack of structural integrity...
我们这是在干啥
What the hell are we doing?
说明了建造的材料不够好
is an obvious downfall of the building material.
但是一旦准备就绪
But once in position and prepped...
太美了
Beautiful.
电点火在这里
Electric match here.
它还是很吸引眼球的
it truly is a sight to behold.
太美了
It's beautiful
这是一门冰制大炮
It's an ice cannon.
但它是否有用呢
And whether it works or not...
瞧瞧这个美人
Look at that beauty.
好的  别站在正前方
All right, don't stand in front.
绝境下的神奇创造马上为您揭晓
the backs-to-the-wall ingenuity is to be celebrated.
好的  准备完毕
All right, we're wired and hot!
实验真正的意义在于创新
What this really is about is innovation,
在于简易的兵器
improvised weaponry,
在于利用你手头的材料
taking what you have
来制作某样又危险又酷的东西
to make something completely dangerous and totally cool.
或许只有一点危险  走着瞧吧
Or maybe a little dangerous. We'll see.
请勿在家尝试本片中的任何实验
Remember, do not try anything you are about to see at home.
我们要把无辜的
In our quest to make the innocent,
2.7克重的乒乓球变得致命
2.7-gram ping-pong ball lethal,
我在网上看到了一个用真空泵的技术
I came across a technique online using a vacuum chamber...
开始
Here we go!
让我们在工作台上达到了
that got us amazing speeds on this bench
每秒170米的速度
of 375 miles per hour.
我的天呐
Holy shit!
我们就想  "那咱们把管道加长吧"
So we thought, "Let's just add some more barrel."
一
One!
这可不行
That's no good.
目前为止  这个方法的结果并不理想
So far, that has yielded pretty much bupkis for us.
怎么回事  完全不对啊
What the fuck? Nothing's making any sense.
86米/秒
但我之后又在网上搜索了相关技术
But, I have, in researching this technique further online,
并发现了一种改装方法
come across a modification to it
或许可以达到我们的目标
that might just give us what we're looking for,
我正准备建一个
And I'm about to build it.
需要使用节流阀
It involves a choke.
使用这个技术
With this new piece of tech,
亚当要将一些火箭科技应用到乒乓球中
Adam's bringing a little rocket science to the ping-pong party.
为了理解这个是什么及能否运作
And to understand what it is and if it works,
亚当要先测试一个短筒原型机
Adam's first testing a short-barrel prototype.
这个装置的一部分看起来很眼熟
Part of this rig is very familiar,
但是添加了节流阀...
But the addition of the choke...
啊! 逗你的
Ah! Kidding.
抽成真空后  我把这个装在这里
After I pull a vacuum, I'll put this on here,
这样炮筒后面就多了一个气压舱
thus making this a sealed pressure chamber behind the barrel.
开始抽真空
Vacuumizing.
抽完真空后
When I feel like I've got a full vacuum,
我将按这个让气压进入筒中
I then hook shot air pressure up into this,
这额外的30到40甚至50万帕的
and the extra 40 to 60 to 80 psi
气压将冲破胶带
that comes out of here will burst this piece of tape,
并按照设定将球加速到更快的速度
sending everything going, supposedly much, much faster.
我希望这个能成功
I really hope this works.
三  二  一
Three, two, one.
高压空气冲破真空
The blast of pressurized air popped the vacuum
并且对小球做了更多的功
and added extra energy to the equation.
但效果如何呢
But just how much?
速度达到了每小时1246公里
779 miles per hour.
亲娘啊
Mama!
1246公里/小时
这才像话嘛
That's what I'm talking about.
亚当的意思是
What Adam's talking about
经历了一番辛苦后
is that after all their hard work,
他们让乒乓球的速度超过了音速
they have a ping-pong ball faster than the speed of sound.
1246公里/小时
音速=1225公里/小时
就是说比这个还快
That's quicker than this...
也比这个快
and this.
那么下一步将做什么呢
So, where next from here?
这是一个有效的概念验证
So, this is now a working proof of concept.
我们发现增加节流阀的方法
We found about this technology of adding a choke,
就如同火箭技术一样
like, like rocket science,
火箭技术中使用节流阀来帮助火箭飞行
rocket science uses a choke to make jets and rockets work,
我们把它添加到这里并在后面加压
and we put it here with some pressure behind it.
成功加速到了每小时1246公里
And we got 779 miles per hour.
所以我们要去一个更大的实验场地
So now we're gonna go to a bigger location.
就是这样的场地
And what a location.
要是咱的工作室在这里该多好啊
Don't you wish this could be our shop?
是啊
Boy, do I.
在这个无与伦比的梅森仓库中
Here at fabulous fort Mason,
亚当和杰米将针对
Adam and Jamie will definitively answer the question,
乒乓球最快飞行速度的问题给出定论
how fast can a table-tennis ball fly?
接好一根了
One down.
并且要测试它的致命性
And then test its lethality
为此他们在搭建超大号的乒乓球发射筒
By super-sizing their prototype ping-pong popgun barrel...
这是最后一根了
That's the last one.
以及一个带节流阀的高压舱
and the pressurized choke chamber.
在工作室里只用了不到70万帕的气压
Back in the shop, they've used less than 100 psi
就把密封胶带压破了
to pop the packing tape vacuum.
1246公里/小时
现在他们要提升至345万帕
Now they're ramping it up to 500.
准备好了吗
Ready?
嗯
Ish.
并且他们希望将这巨大的冲击
And they want to deliver that massive blast...
别伤到我的胳膊
I hope you don't break my arm.
在瞬间释放
fast.
我觉得挺不错的
I think that was pretty good.
我也觉得挺不错的
把这个重磅炸弹连接就位后
And with the big beast hooked up and ready for action,
下面来介绍一下实验流程
here's how it's gonna go down.
从头看到现在的观众们
The setup out here should be pretty familiar
应该对这个场景布置很熟悉
to anyone who's been watching thus far,
除了现在使用的炮筒有46米长
except for the fact that the barrel's 150 feet long.
在真空筒后面是我们的高压气舱
Behind our vacuum tube, of course, is our pressure chamber,
里面的气压高达345万帕
and pressured to 500 pounds per square inch of pressure.
整个装置由这个拉杆启动
The whole business is activated by this lever,
扳下拉杆的工具就是...
which we will set off with...
这个
this.
筒内空气已抽干
And so, with the air evacuated from the barrel
节流阀也已就绪  杰米上场了
and the choke ready to charge, Jamie steps up to the plate.
开始了  345万帕  46米炮筒
Here we go, 500 psi, 150-foot-long barrel,
倒数三  二  一  发射
in three, two, one, do it!
跟变魔术似的
It is like a magic trick here.
乒乓球刚刚还在眼前
I was looking at the ping-pong ball,
然后一眨眼就没了
and then it just wasn't there.
发射
Do it!
完全感觉不到它是飞走的
It wasn't even, like, I had a sensation of it moving.
哔的一下就消失了
It just blip! Whisked out of existence.
本以为发射正常  直到看到证据
Which bodes well ballistically, until the evidence is found...
乒乓球只剩这点残骸了
There's very little of the ping-pong ball left.
并且观察了高速摄像
...and then examined on the high-speed.
还没出炮筒时它就碎了
It's not even left the barrel, and it's totally shattered.
这是个问题
That's a bit of a problem.
问题是他们需要一个完整的乒乓球
The problem being they need the full weight of an aerodynamic,
来提供最大的杀伤力
intact ball for maximum mortal damage.
但好消息是
The good news is
速度达到了每小时1748公里
It was going at a speed of 1,086 miles per hour.
这真快啊
That's pretty fast.
1748公里/小时
确实很快
That is pretty fast.
尽管我们的乒乓球达到了1.4倍音速
Even though our ping-pong ball was going at mach 1.4,
这当然很赞  但我不能说那很成功
which is amazing, I can't say that that was successful.
因为它飞出炮筒时已经不能称作乒乓球了
Because it wasn't a ping-pong ball when it left the barrel.
所以我们要把这个炮筒裁剪到6米长
So, we're gonna cut this barrel at 20 feet.
并且降低压强
We're gonna lower the overall pressure.
开始啦
Here we go.
6米炮筒  207万帕  正常速度释放气压
20-foot barrel, 300 psi, semi-slow release.
我们不清楚结果会怎么样
We're not sure what's gonna happen.
三
Three...
但实验的结果能让我们明白
But whatever does ought to really help inform us
发生了什么
about what's going on.
二  准备发射
Two... So, here we go.
一  射
One, go.
砰的一声真悦耳
That was an ever-loving smack of a bang.
发射成功  球还在地上滚
That was a hell of a bang, and that ball is rolling.
球完好无损
The ball is intact.
完好无损  并且十分疯狂
Intact and insane.
从高速摄像中我们看到
Confirmed on the high-speed
世界纪录  1770公里/小时
它的时速达到了1770公里的新纪录
at a world-record 1,100 miles an hour,
这个仅有2.7克重的小乒乓球
the delicate 2.7-gram ping-pong ball
飞行速度达到了大型客机的两倍
is traveling twice as fast as a jumbo jet,
就和子弹一样快
as fast as a speeding bullet.
现在我们想说
Now we are talking.
我们将47米长的炮筒
We went from a 150-foot barrel
缩减为6米  并加上207万帕气压
To a 20-foot barrel with 300 p.S.I. Behind it.
现在我们要验证这个炮筒射出的
And now it's time to find out if the 1,100 miles per hour
时速1770公里的乒乓球
we got out of the end of that barrel...
我想我们准备好了
I think we're ready.
是否致命呢
is in fact lethal.
致命的乒乓球  这是我们的实验目标
Lethal balls. That's what we're looking for.
亚当和杰米马上要测试
Adam and Jamie are about to test
他们的超音速乒乓球的致命性
the lethality of their supersonic balls.
在此之前他们想先轰击杰米的幸运球拍
But before that, they want to shoot Jamie's lucky bat.
它不知道自己在面临着什么
It has no idea what's in store for it.
它现在完全知道要发生什么了
It totally knows what's in store for it.
三  二  一  发射
Three, two, one, go.
震撼人心
Holy batman.
这是你的问题了
There's your problem.
真是件漂亮的杰作
That is a beautiful, beautiful object.
这就是时速1770公里的乒乓球的威力
That is an 1,100-mile-per-hour ping-pong ball,
女士们先生们
ladies and gentlemen.
但这致命吗
But is it lethal?
在18世纪西伯利亚的一个寒冬
In the depths of an 18th-century Siberian winter,
一支绝望的被困军队发挥他们的创造力
A desperate, siege-bound army used their imagination
使用他们手边最充足的资源
and their most abundant resource
他们想出了使用冰制大炮的主意
and came up with a working ice cannon.
这个庄严的运用普通物材制成的大炮
It's been 300 years since this majestic,
理论上曾在300年前有效御敌
Macgyver-like solution has supposedly worked.
它能打倒那些可怕的泡沫军队吗
Will it take out the fearsome foam army?
关键的时刻到了
It's the moment of truth.
冰制大炮终极实验
All right, this is ice cannon final experiment.
倒数三  二  一
In three, two, one.
大炮仍完好无损
And the cannon is still intact!
目前  一切顺利
So far, so good.
出口速度达到每小时321公里
With a muzzle velocity of 200 miles an hour,
炮弹轻易穿越137米的实验场
the cannonball easily covered the 150 yards
直达目标区间
to the target zone.
看这个
Look at this.
这就是冰制炮弹  简直太棒了
This is the ice cannonball. This is awesome.
炮弹第一次发射就满足了两个参数要求
We took our first shot, and we reached two of the parameters.
其一  我们达到了要求的距离
One, we made the distance,
1 距离 = 137米
2 显著伤害
3 可重复使用
而且  我们的大炮状态仍然良好
and our cannon is still in good condition.
我们可以再发射一次
We can take another shot.
唯一没能达到的就是我们想看到的显著伤害
We just didn't get the damage that we were looking for.
但对于一个300年都没使用过的武器
But for something that hasn't been done in 300 years,
这已经很不错了
that's pretty good.
不仅是很不错
Not just pretty good.
这支队伍成功的发射了用水制成的大炮
The team successfully fired a cannon made of water.
但以他们严格的标准而言
But according to their strict criteria,
这还不算成功
It's not yet successful.
我知道这枚炮弹能直达那些人站的位置
Well, I know the cannonball made it all the way to the guys,
但我希望这次它能制造点伤害
but I'm hoping this time, it actually does some damage.
当说起一枚炮弹
So when you're talking about the damage
能造成的伤害时
that a cannonball can cause,
其中最重要的就是动能
you're talking about kinetic energy.
动能取决于两个因素  质量和速度
Kinetic energy depends on two things, mass and velocity.
动能 = 1/2mv
质量取决于炮弹本身
Now, the mass is determined by the ball itself.
因此  如果我们希望有更多动能
So if we want more kinetic energy,
我们需要做的就是加快速度
what we need to do is increase the velocity.
现在  在正常情况下
Now, under normal circumstances,
你要做的就是加入更多的黑火药
all you'd need to do is add more black powder,
它发射时就会更快了
and it comes out faster.
但如果我们放入更多的黑火药
But the more black powder we put in,
大炮就更有可能在造成致命伤害前
the greater risk of destroying the cannon itself
自己土崩瓦解了
before we get a lethal shot.
现在  加入等量的黑火药
So with the same amount of black powder
并将弹道扭转
and a tweaked trajectory...
我们好激动
We are hot.
这一次  冰冷的大炮
will the ice-cold cannon this time
能化身冷酷的杀手吗
be an ice-cold killer?
冰制大炮  倒数三  二  一
This is the ice cannon, in three, two, one!
答案是否定的
The answer is... no.
尽管这次炮弹发射涵盖的距离更长
Although the ball more than covered the distance,
直接从靶子头上飞过
sailing over the heads of the targets,
这个流言还是触礁了
this myth is on the rocks.
我喜欢这个
I like this.
我以后就要这么弄碎我的冰块
I'm gonna start crushing my ice this way.
火与冰的结合
Mixing fire and ice
一般不会被认为很危险
was never likely to be a dangerous cocktail.
但鉴于材料上有严格的限制
But given the severe limitations of the material,
这份巧思还真是令人难以置信
it was an incredible effort of ingenuity.
这条流言曾多次看似可行
This is the myth that was almost plausible so many times.
一开始形势真的太好了
It was looking so good in the beginning.
我们从制作冰制炮弹开始
We started out with our ice cannonballs.
以高速发射真正的炮弹
Fired out of a real cannon at high speed.
然后我们开始研制后膛
Then we went to the breeches,
我们找到了一种可以承受
and we found a breech size that would hold
合理分量黑火药的后膛尺寸
a reasonable amount of black powder.
我们将零件组装成一个真实尺寸的大炮
We put the whole thing together, built a full-size cannon,
并带来这里直面我们的敌人
brought it out here to face our army.
又一次  看起来很有希望
And it was, again, looking very promising.
但不幸的是
But unfortunately,
那一枚本有可能造成最大伤害的炮弹
on the one that would've caused the most damage,
直接飞过了敌军脑袋
which is the one that sailed over the army's heads
打在了墙上
and hit the wall,
就在那时  大炮自己爆炸了
that's the one where the cannon itself exploded.
如果这个流言可行的话
And for this myth to be plausible,
伤害  射程和可重复利用三者缺一不可
we have to have damage and range and reusability all in one.
可惜最终还是没有实现
And that just never happened.
因此  非常不幸
So, unfortunately,
我们不得不终结这个流言了
I think we have to bust this one.
我一点也不高兴
And I'm not happy about it.
流言终结
乒乓球
Table tennis,
地球上最快的球类运动之一
one of the fastest ball sports on the planet.
但这个速度还不足以致命
But surely it can never be fast enough... to be fatal.
现在到了最后阶段
So it all comes down to this,
一枚时速1770公里的乒乓球
a ping-pong ball going 1,100 miles per hour...
发射
Go.
1770公里/小时
与肉体的对抗
versus flesh.
谁会获胜呢
Which one's gonna win?
我们这就来看看
We're about to find out.
关于我们的致命性实验
For our lethality test,
今天由一块猪肩肉来充当人类的替身
today's human analogue will be played by a pork shoulder,
也可以被叫做猪臀
otherwise known as a pork butt,
因为猪有四个肩膀  其中两个是臀部
because pork has four shoulders and two of them are butts.
真的  不信你自己去查
It's true. Look it up.
问题是史上最高速的球是无损的从猪臀上
The question is, will the world-record-breaking ball
弹开还是以致命之力穿透猪臀
bounce harmlessly off the butt or penetrate with lethal force?
是时候让能量具现化了
Time to turn some potential energy into some actual energy.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
-我准备好了  -好的
- I'm ready. - Okay.
短管  207万帕  致命性实验
Short barrel, 300 p.s.i., lethality test
目标猪臀
with a pork butt
倒数三  二  一  发射
in three, two, one, go.
这可真是一阵冲击波啊  真的
That was a blast... Literally.
但我们的猪朋友还好吗
But how did our porcine pal fare?
让我们看看造成的伤害
All right, let's look at the damage.
兄弟
Dude.
这里有一个深达3.8厘米的
There's, like, flesh trauma
肉体创伤
going down an inch and a half into here.
这可真不可思议
That's impressive.
我必须承认  如果你事先问我
I must admit, if you had asked me beforehand,
我会告诉你我认为乒乓球
I would've told you that I thought the ping-pong ball
会从猪肉上弹开
was going to bounce right off of the pig.
因为这两个物体的质量让我认为
I thought the mass of the two objects was such
乒乓球真的不可能造成这么大的伤害
that the ball really wouldn't do that much damage.
它造成这么大的伤害我真的很吃惊
I am shocked by how much damage it did.
那玩意儿真的穿过去了
Now, that thing actually penetrated.
这个是乒乓球形状的
That's ping-pong-ball-shaped.
真令人惊讶
That is a shocker.
被打到肯定很疼
That would hurt.
但我认为仍得认定这个为不致命的一击
But I think we still need to call that this a non-lethal hit.
它没能完全的穿透这块肉
It did not penetrate all the way through the flesh
或者打出一个洞来什么的
or leave some gaping wound,
除非走运  否则这就是不致命的
and barring some lucky hit, that is not a deadly hit.
这个确实对肉体造成了伤害但并不致命
This is a substantial flesh wound, but it ain't lethal.
是的  尽管极高的压强
Yep, despite the extreme air pressure
和一个超光速的球让猪肉飞出去了
and a supersonic ball making the pig fly,
火腿上并无致命性的伤害
the impact did not mortally harm the ham.
那最终裁决是
So, final verdict?
一枚马赫数为1.4的乒乓球
A mach 1.4 ping-pong ball
可能只不过是史上最快的乒乓球而已
might just be the fastest ping-pong ball in history...
非常危险  却并不致命
Extremely dangerous, but not lethal.
一点也不致命  流言被终结了
Not lethal at all. The myth is busted.
-确实终结了  -我们出去吧
- Busted, it is. - Let's get out of here.
流言终结